[Music]
hi guys this is step and welcome to my
channel in this channel we talked about
personal finance productivity and
adulting in general so if you're
interested in this topics please
subscribe to this channel hit the
notification Bell like this video and
share this to your
[Music]
friends as mentioned in my previous
video guys it's about life insurance as
the different types of life insurances
mainly focused just a term life
insurance so I said that I have a ter
ter life insurance that I want to
discuss from sunlife which is called the
sun lifee assure but
disclaimer life insurance agent or
financial advisor so I am I just have a
life insurance from this
company and this is a term insurance so
let's discuss about Sun Life assure so
so Sun Life assure is para Life
protection coupled with critical illness
protection death benefits and then if
ever
critical
Illness but for you to Simply understand
this one it is like death benefits or
critical illness whichever comes first
so for example critical illness and
amount coverage for this policy or for
your plan determinate death benefits
socy or once the death benefit Or the
critical illness benefit has been
claimed the policy terminates so
whichever comes first which I think is
good amage for example
illness as the benefit for critical
illness for example 1 million 1 million
amount policy
so 1 million at a lower premium compared
riders for critical
illness coverage so for me good deal Sun
Life assur so as mentioned policy guys
Sun Life assur is a packaged life
insurance with critical illness benefits
so you life insurance or critical
illness whichever comes first and then
policy since this is a term insurance up
to 70 years old you coverage so you're
insured for both death and critical
illness up to age 70 but you need to
consider that it automatically renews
every 5 years and then premium adjust M
every 5th year anniversary policy
so concept so 1 to 5 years fixed
premium so in the sixth to 10th year
adjust premium amount and when I say
adjust amount premium but when I saw the
policy
guys and then you can
choose so for
example up to 50 years old the
time
on insurance for protection if
ever until age 50
so policy up to age 50 gon so you just
need to consider that
one so I will show you later the
premiums that you can possibly pay for
this and then coverage for critical
illness guys is 36 mention 36 critical
illness that they can cover so you can
take a look at the critical illness here
so 36 and S policy
guys
details just read the policy then so
summary critical illness cover so
conditions for the critical illness once
the critical illness benefit has been
claimed again emphasize the policy
terminates and then condition claim
critical illness that
it must occur more than 90 days after
the date the policy comes into Force
so critical illness so for example
policy is enforced today 30 days after
critical
illness
shoulder
illness based on their condition it must
occur more than 90 days after the date
that the policy comes into force and
then P other conditions guys so they
will not pay the benefit if pre-existing
illness or recurring critical illness
which are diagnosed prior to the
effective date of this
policy Insurance out form
soclose medical history so you need to
be honest about that because it will
really affect your life insurance so
possible preexisting
illness his
life insurance company by that it is
possible deine request if everal ill
later from the start
so
am from the start and then they will not
pay also for the benefit if it is
arising from congenital abnormalities
HIV related illness illnesses arising
from suicide self-inflicted injuries
taking or or absorbing accidentally
intoxicating liquor poison drugs
narcotic or
medicin conditions so just be aware of
this from just in
case
illness critical illness benefits so
read your policy for you to be aware of
this these
things critical
illness so read the policy before
signing it so simple so you can have a
death benefit protection critical
illness coverage which terminates if
ever so for exampal illness benefit so
the policy terminates so and then
critical illness covered so which is
good package insurance and critical ill
so guys I will show you a sample now
quotation from sunlife
before 25 years old coverage is 1
million and then rers accidental death
benefit your or you ADB which is also 1
million so meaning to say guys if you
died from accidents so you can claim the
1 million death benefit and then my
additional sh Riders and then another 1
million benefit for the ADB or the
accidental death benefit so 2 million
all in all if ever you died from
accident menang face amount the policy
has a face amount of 1 million and then
the critical illness or life insurance
coverage is also 1 million but then
again as mentioned earlier the the
policy terminates upon payment of
critical illness or life insurance
coverage so whichever comes
first critical illness 1 million the
policy terminates death benefits so how
much so in this
case guys premium is initial annual
premium is
9,580 25 years old so again to fix for
everyone H cuz it depends on your age so
at 25 years old 1 million
coverage annual premium is just
9,580 cheap
Guys 1 million
cage 36 30,000 up annual premium they
also have other payment terms so
quarterly or semiannual per guys
cheaper annual premium quarterly or
semiannual premiums so notice quarterly
premium
26345 so if im multiply four four
quarters in a year parasa 10,000
something
if in one go
9,500 something so cheaper if annualize
payment so it's up to you if son must
afford so S I chose quarterly premium so
y sample n premiums so this is the
premium schedule so mode of payment is
quarterly so 2634 guys quarter to so
every quarter y Bay for the next 5 years
so cheap so that's 3 months
2,634 but again I
mentioned every 5 years Reen policy
sojust
amount so notice s year 6 to 10
2678 so it increases gradually every 5
years of renewability so from 11th year
to 15th year change Nam man so it really
changes
but and it depends how long you want to
be covered so for me it's really
affordable for a 1 million face amount
of a policy possible assured critical
illness benefit so for me it's a good
deal so guys consider this one
if
for AG life insurance and critical
illness whichever comes first so that's
it guys I hope you learned a lot from
this video if you have other questions
please comment down below and in the
next video I would also like to discuss
one whole life insurance from Sun Life
which is called Sun Fit and Well so stay
tuned for the next videos do not forget
to like comment and subscribe bye